Finding Aid for Gunnar Birkerts papers 1930-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Project Files
  - Fisher Administrative Center, University of Detroit, Michigan, 1964-1966
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on three sheets of tracing paper, 12x11-1/4 to 12x13-1/2 inches, two sheets of yellow paper, 8-1/2x11 inches, and one index card with notes, 3x5 inches (Map-case 1, Folder 8)
  - University of Kentucky School of Architecture City Hall Design Charette, Wind City Project (study), 1964
    - Project Files
      - Architect's Conceptual Statement (Box 9)
      - "UK Design Charette," The Kentucky Architect, Pp. 9-17, December 1964 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Design Development Drawings., Undated
        - First Floor Plan, Elevations and Sections, Pencil and colored pencil drawings on six sheets of vellum, 12x34-3/4 to 26-3/4x36 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 1)
      - "City Halls and Emergency Operating Centers," published by Office of Civil Defense, 1965; 11x17 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 1)
  - Freeman Residence, Grand Rapids, Michigan, 1964-1966
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Important Early Floor Plan Showing Beginning of the Concept of Superimposing a Radial upon an Orthogonal Grid], untitled, Pencil-on-vellum drawing and blue-line print with ink sketches and notations, 17-1/2x28 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Red crayon drawing on tracing paper, 12x18 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 2)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Red crayon drawing on tracing paper, 19-1/2x23-3/4 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 2)
  - Lincoln Elementary School, Columbus, Indiana, 1965-1967
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Schematic Design Drawing., Undated
        - [Important Drawing], untitled, Pencil on vellum drawing, 17-1/2x28 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 2)
  - Livonia Public Library, Livonia, Michigan, 1965-1967
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Red ink sketches on five sheets of yellow paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 2)
  - Lewis Residence, Bloomfield Hills, Michigan, 1965-1967
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue ink sketches on shirt cardboard, 8x12 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue ink sketches on two pieces of shirt cardboard, 8x12 inches, and purple crayon sketch on tracing paper, 12x21 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 2)
  - Michigan Technological University, Sault Ste. Marie Branch, Dormitory and Food Service Center, 1965-1968
    - Project Files
      - Specifications and Construction Drawings. Microfilm prints, 05/17/1966 (Box 10)
  - Tougaloo College Master Plan, Tougaloo, Mississippi (unbuilt project), 1965-1971
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on five sheets of tracing paper, 5-1/4x6 to 8-1/2x9-1/2 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 3)
        - [Study Sketch], untitled, Brown ink drawing on tracing paper, 18x17-1/2 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 3)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink and purple crayon sketch on tracing paper, 17-3/4x21 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 3)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on yellow paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 3)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on shirt cardboard, 7-3/4x9-3/4 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 3)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Brown ink sketch on tracing paper, 7-1/4x9-1/2 inches, 8x10-inch black and white photographic print and 3-1/2x5-inch negative (Map-case 2, Folder 3)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on ten sheets of tracing paper, 6-1/2x10-3/4 to 24x24 inches, and one sheet of yellow paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 3)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Three blue-line prints, 14-1/2x24 to 24x36 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 3)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Digital image only of black ink sketches on vellum and tracing paper
        - [Sketches], untitled, Digital image only of black ink sketches on shirt cardboard
        - [Sketches], untitled, Digital image only of blue ink sketches on vellum, August 5th
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Pencil drawing on tracing paper, 21-1/4x31-1/2 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 3)
  - Tougaloo College Library, Tougaloo, Mississippi, 1967-1972
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Study Sketches of Structural System for Academic Matrix], untitled, Ink sketches on shirt cardboard, 8x11-3/4 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 3)
        - [Massing Study], untitled, Ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x25-1/2 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 3)
  - Massey Ferguson North American Operations Offices, Des Moines, Iowa (unbuilt project), 1966
    - Project Files
      - Architect's Conceptual Statement (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Section Perspective], untitled, Pencil drawing on vellum, 12x17 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 4)
  - Glen Oaks Community College, Centreville, Michigan, 1966-1971
    - Project Files
      - Architect's Conceptual Statement and Design Presentation Notes with Sketch, 02/02/1966 (Box 9)
      - Specifications and Construction Drawings. Microfilm prints and 11/23/66, 02/20/1966 (Box 10)
      - Alternate Bidding Documents, Addendum #1 and Construction Drawings. Microfilm prints and 11/5/73, 10/30/1973 (Box 10)
      - Vocational Addition
        - Specifications and Construction Drawings. Microfilm prints, 7/15/70 (Box 10)
        - Addenda #1 and #3. Microfilm prints, 09/22/1970; 09/29/1970 (Box 10)
        - Specifications, Addendum #1 and Construction Drawings. Microfilm prints and 1/27/71, 01/18/1971 (Box 10)
      - Newspaper and Journal Articles, 1967-1968 (Box 10)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Sketches], untitled, Brown ink sketches on two sides of shirt cardboard, with notation, "see also other side," 6x8 inches, 1/23/66 (Map-case 2, Folder 4)
        - GB Sketch #26 [of Site Plan], Black ink and colored pencil sketch on tracing paper, 12x24-1/2 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 4)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - GB Sketch #18 [of Site Plan], Pencil and colored pencil drawing on vellum, 16-1/2x19-3/4 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 4)
  - Church of St. Bede, Southfield, Michigan, 1966-1969
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Brown ink sketches on two pieces of shirt cardboard, 8x14 inches, and one piece of notebook paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 4)
  - United States Pavilion of Expo '67, Montreal, Canada (unbuilt project), 1967
    - Project Files
      - Outline Proposal to U.S. Information Agency, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Ford Motor Company Pavilion of Hemisfair '68, San Antonio, Texas, 1967-1968
    - Project Files
      - Architect's Conceptual Statement (Box 9)
      - Newspaper Articles, 1967-1968 (Box 9)
  - United States Pavilion of Hemisfair '68, San Antonio, Texas (unbuilt project), 1967-1968
    - Project Files
      - Preliminary Estimate to U.S. Department of Commerce for the Architectural Design of the United States Pavilion at the Hemisfair, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Vocational Technical Institute Campus Master Plan, Carbondale, Illinois (unbuilt project), 1967
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Brown ink sketches on shirt cardboard, 8x12 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 5)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Black and red ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x24-1/2 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 5)
        - [Sketches], untitled. Black and red ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x17 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 5)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Brown ink sketch on shirt cardboard, 8x8-3/4 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 5)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Brown and red ink sketches on three sheets of tracing paper, 12x10-1/2 to 12x25-1/4 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 5)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on shirt cardboard, with sketch of Tougaloo Library structural system on reverse, 8-1/2x12 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 5)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on two Air Canada ticket folders, 7-1/4x8-1/4 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 5)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on Delta Air Lines "Seat Occupied" sign, with notation, "This M Plan will never be complete," 4x8-1/2 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 5)
  - Mount Olive Baptist Church, Detroit, Michigan, 1967-1970
    - Project Files
      - Specifications, Bulletins #1 and #2, and Construction Drawings. Microfilm prints, 9/8/69, 10/31/1973; 11/21/1973 (Box 10)
  - Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1967-1973
    - Project Files
      - "Construction of A Steel Suspended Structure". Motion picture produced by Balthazar Korab, 08/01/1977 (Box 5)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketch], untitled, Brown ink sketch with notations on notebook paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 5)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Brown ink sketch with numerical calculations on notebook paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 5)
  - Amsterdam City Hall Competition, Amsterdam, Netherlands (unbuilt project), 1968
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketch], untitled, Brown ink sketch on tracing paper, 16-3/4x22 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 5)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Brown and blue ink sketches on shirt cardboard, 8x12 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 5)
  - Corning Public Library (First Proposal), Corning, New York (unbuilt project), 1969
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketch of Building as a Bridge, Representing the Beginning of Polygonal Thought in Gunnar Birkerts' Work], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x19-3/4 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 6)
        - [Sketch of Building as a Bridge], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 11-1/2x12 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 6)
        - [Sketch of Building as a Bridge], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x12-1/4 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 6)
        - [Sketches of Building as a Bridge], untitled, Ink sketches on two sheets of tracing paper, 12x27-1/2 & 12x33 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 6)
        - [Sketch of Building as a Bridge], untitled, Ink sketch on two sheets of tracing paper, one initialed, 12x13-3/4 & 12x18 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 6)
        - [Sketches of Building as a Bridge], untitled, Ink sketches on shirt cardboard, 8x14 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 6)
  - Corning Public Library (Final Proposal), Corning, New York (unbuilt project), 1969
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on two pieces of shirt cardboard, 7-1/4x8 & 8x11 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 6)
  - Metropolitan Federal Savings and Loan Bank, Southfield, Michigan (unbuilt project), 1969
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x15 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 6)
        - G.B. Original Sketch #38, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x17 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 6)
        - [Early Sketches], untitled, Red and black ink sketches on three sheets of tracing paper, 12x15-1/2 to 12x19-1/2 inches, and one sheet of yellow paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 6)
  - Duluth Public Library, Duluth, Minnesota, 1969-1980
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - Building Section Study with Skylight, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 11-1/4x24-1/2 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 6)
        - Skylight Study Section, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 11-1/2x20 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 6)
        - Skylight Study, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 8x19-1/4 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 6)
        - Duluth [Plaza] Bench., 08/16/1982; Green ink sketch on graph paper with notation "over Missouri," 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 2, Folder 6)
  - IBM Corporate Computer Center, Sterling Forest, New York, 1970-1972
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on tracing paper, initialed, 12x25-1/2 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 1)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Black and brown ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x23-3/4 inches
        - [Sketches], untitled, Brown ink sketches on tracing paper, initialed, 12x26 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 1)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Black and brown ink sketches on eight sheets of tracing paper, 12x12 to 12x30 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 1)
  - Contemporary Arts Museum, Houston, Texas, 1970-1972
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches
        - [Sketches], untitled, Black and red ink sketches on tracing paper, 12x16-1/2 inches, undated (Map-case 3, Folder 1)
        - [New Entrance], untitled, undated, Blue ink sketches on two sheets of tracing paper, 12x12 & 12x18 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 1)
          (with letter from Museum Director Suzanne Delehanty 11/19/91)
  - State University of New York, Purchase College Dance Instructional Facility, Purchase, New York, 1970-1976
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketches #17], untitled, Black ink sketches on shirt cardboard, 8x10-3/4 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches #18], untitled, Black ink sketches on shirt cardboard, 8x14 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches #19-20], untitled, Ink sketches on two pieces of shirt cardboard, 8x14 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches #21-22], untitled, Ink sketches on two pieces of shirt cardboard, 8x14 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 2)
  - Subterranean Urban Systems Study, Graham Foundation Grant, 1971-1974
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on spiral notebook paper, 8-1/4x10-3/4 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on spiral notebook paper, 8-1/4x10-3/4 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on spiral notebook paper, 8-1/4x10-3/4 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 2)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Digital image only of blue ink sketches on spiral notebook paper, initialed, 8-1/4x10-3/4 inches
        - [Sketches], untitled, Black and blue ink sketches on twelve sheets of spiral notebook paper, one initialed, 8-1/4x10-3/4 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 2)
        - Sketch Book, Blue and black ink conceptual sketches and notes on thirty-two sheets of paper, cover signed, 9x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 2)
  - Ford Motor Company Visitor Reception Center (Scheme I), Dearborn, Michigan (unbuilt project), 1971
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Scheme 1], untitled, Ink sketch on white paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 3)
        - [Scheme 1], untitled, Ink sketches on three sheets of white paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 3)
  - Ford Motor Company Visitor Reception Center (Scheme II), Dearborn, Michigan, 1972-1975
    - Project Files
      - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Federal Reserve Bank of Helena, Montana (unbuilt project), 1972
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Brown ink sketches on two sheets of "Grand Hotel, Stockholm" memo pad paper, 6x8-1/4 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 3)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Brown ink sketches on graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 3)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Brown ink sketches on reverse of "Restaurant Prinsen, Stockholm" menu, 10-3/4x15-1/2 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 3)
  - Washington Monument Visitor Center Competition, Washington, DC (unbuilt project), 1972
    - Project Files
      - [Proposal], untitled, undated (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Conceptual Sketches], untitled, Ink drawings with notations on one sheet of "The Statler Hilton" stationery, 6x9-1/2 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 3)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - G.B. Worksheet, #43, Ink drawing on reverse of blue-line print, 14-1/4x18-3/4 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 3)
  - General Motors Transportation Studies: Dual Mode Transit System, 1973-1974
    - Project Files
      - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 9)
  - Municipal Fire Station, Corning, New York, 1973-1974
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Topographical Site Plan], untitled, Ink, pencil and colored pencil drawings on three sheets of tracing paper, 17-1/2x32-1/2 to 34-1/4x46 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 3)
        - [Elevations and Isometric], untitled, Pencil drawings on three sheets of tracing paper, 17-1/2x36 to 17-1/2x47 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 3)
  - University of Michigan Law Library Addition, 1974-1981
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Alternative Scheme], untitled, Blue ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x17-3/4 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 4)
        - [Final Underground Scheme], untitled, Ink sketch on shirt cardboard, 7-3/4x14 inches, 8x10-inch black-and-white photographic print, and 3-1/2x5-inch negative (Map-case 3, Folder 4)
        - [Final Underground Scheme], untitled, Ink sketches on two pieces of shirt cardboard, 8x13-3/4 & 8x14 inches, and 3-1/2x5-inch negative (Map-case 3, Folder 4)
  - IBM Office Building, Southfield, Michigan, 1974-1979
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Green ink sketches on two sheets of graph paper, one initialed, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 4)
  - U. S. Embassy Office Building, Helsinki, Finland (unbuilt project), 1975
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Green and black ink sketch on tracing paper, 18x27 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
        - [Roof Study], untitled, Ink and blue pencil sketches on tracing paper, 15-1/2x18 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
        - [Roof Study], untitled, Ink sketches on tracing paper, 17x18 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
        - Embassy Window [Studies] (#49), Blue ink sketches on notebook paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
        - Embassy Window Studies, Blue ink sketches on notebook paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
        - [Concept Explanation Sketch], untitled, Ink sketches on four sheets of spiral notebook paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
        - [Drawings], untitled, Ink drawings on two sheets of tracing paper, 12x15-1/2 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
        - [Plan], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper with Birkerts' initials and notations to his staff, 12x16-3/4 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Green and brown ink sketch on tracing paper, 17-3/4x30 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
  - Embassy Prototype for Foreign Buildings Office, Washington, D.C. (unbuilt project), 1975
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches
        - ["Ideal Embassy"], untitled, 5/7/75, Black and orange ink sketch on graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
  - Housing Competition, Amman, Jordan, 1976
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Schematic Design Drawings,11/12/76, Photographic prints, 11-3/4x16-1/2 inches, except as noted
        - Site Plan, Print with pantone, 11-3/4x20-1/2 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
        - Housing Units [Diagrams], 3 prints (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
        - Typical Living Units [Floor Plans] (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
        - Housing Cluster Section (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
        - Day Care School [Floor Plans] (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
        - Civic Center Parking [Floor Plan] (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
        - Civic Center and Mosque Plan and Section (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
        - Civic Center and Mosque [Plan] (Map-case 3, Folder 5)
  - Corning Museum of Glass, Corning, New York, 1976-1980
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Corning Museum of Glass I Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Ink sketch on blue-line print, 9-1/2x18-1/4 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 6)
        - [Site Plan], untitled, Black and brown ink sketches on three blue-line prints, 9-1/2x18-1/4 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 6)
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 6)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Ink sketches on three sheets of graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 6)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Brown ink sketches with notes on envelope of the "Grand Hotel, Stockholm, Sweden," 7x6-1/2 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 6)
      - Corning Museum of Glass II Conceptual Sketches. Undated, except as noted
        - [Early Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on graph paper with notation "Pferdestall (Horse Barn Bar), Zurich, Sat, October 5," 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 6)
        - Early Concept Study, Ink sketches on graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 6)
        - [Early Concept Study], untitled, Black and green ink drawing on tracing paper, 18x23 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 6)
        - [Concept Explanation Sketch], untitled, Ink sketches on three sheets of spiral notebook paper, two signed, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 6)
        - [Concept Studies], untitled, Colored cut-outs on four sheets of colored paper, 18-3/4x26 to 19-1/2x27-1/2 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 6)
  - Federated Department Stores Office Building, Cincinnati, Ohio (unbuilt project), 1977
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Sight Line Studies], untitled, Ink drawings on three sheets of graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 7)
  - Unity of the Infinite Presence Church, Warren, Michigan (unbuilt project), 1978
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketch], untitled, Ink sketch on tracing paper, 12x19-1/2 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 7)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue ink sketches on two sheets of memo pad paper, 5x8 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 7)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Brown and black ink sketches on nine sheets of loose-leaf notebook and graph paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 7)
      - Schematic Design Drawings., Undated
        - [Floor Plans], untitled, Pencil, red pencil and ink drawings on two sheets of tracing paper, 11-3/4x23, and one sheet of vellum, 15x21 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 7)
  - Chrysler Corporation Master Plan, Highland Park, Michigan (unbuilt project), 1978
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - Master Plan Concept, Green ink sketch on shirt cardboard, initialed, 8x14 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 7)
  - J. A. Citrin Sons Company Office Building, Bingham Farms, Michigan (unbuilt project), 1979
    - Project Files
      - Newspaper Articles, 1979 (Box 9)
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Brown ink sketches on steno pad paper with notation "Il Buco" (Restaurant), 6x9 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 8)
        - [Sketches], untitled, Colored ink and pencil sketches on four sheets of steno pad paper, 6x9 inches, and one sheet each of graph and notebook paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 8)
  - Muiznieks Residence, Kalamazoo, Michigan (unbuilt project), 1979
    - Architectural Drawings
      - Conceptual Sketches., Undated
        - [Sketches], untitled, Blue and brown ink sketches on three sheets of tracing paper, 12x15 to 18x19-1/2 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 8)
        - [Roof], untitled, Black and blue ink sketches on spiral notebook paper, 8-1/2x11 inches (Map-case 3, Folder 8)